Web & Mobile Backend & Frontend Full Stack Developer

Contractor - MaryLine Engineers E.I.R.L

Prof. Romel Gomez

romel@maryline.io
(+51) 980653479

https://www.linkedin.com/in/romelgomez/
https://github.com/romelgomez

https://calendly.com/romel-maryline/30min

Romel is a skilled backend & frontend developer with over 10 years of experience, with a track record of building high-value software solutions. Experienced with tests, and familiar with microservices. He loves collaborating with multidisciplinary teams, delivering exceptional products, and continually seeking to learn new technologies. He seeks a position to bring a combination of technical expertise and forward-thinking innovation, ensuring robust and efficient solutions to drive digital transformation and business success.

SKILLS

Back-End	NestJS, Python, Node, Java, Golang
Front-End	NextJS, React, Angular, Typescript, Jquery, AstroJS
Mobile	Expo, React Native, iOS Swift
Search Engines	Algolia, <u>Meilisearch</u>
ORMs	Prisma, TypeORM
Database	PostgreSQL, MySQL, <u>Supabase</u> , Firebase
DevOps	Bash, Docker, Google Cloud
Monorepo	NX.dev, Pantsbuild
APIs	<u>Databricks</u> , Stripe API
SEO	Google Analytics, Google Tag Manager
NoCode	Retool
Design	Figma



















WORK EXPERIENCE

Backend Developer maergo.com

Mar. 2024 – June. 2024 Austing, TX · Remote

Maergo.com was a package delivery service provider. Unfortunately, the company has closed its operations; Ref: <u>link</u>.

Responsibilities

- > Build a CVS load view in Retool that accelerates the business data loading time by one week.
- > Build a python scraper that collects and normalizes data from various airlines, and then saves it in <u>Databricks</u>.

Full Stack Developer 2ulaundry.com Feb. 2020 – Jan. 2024 Charlotte, NC · Remote

2ulaundry.com is a laundry and dry cleaning service that picks up, cleans, and delivers your clothes in as little as 1 business day.

Responsibilities

- > Build and maintain large software platforms using Next.js, and Expo.
- > Implement Algolia as a search engine to perform quick and personalized searches of customers' orders.
- > Develop three React Native apps: one for drivers to track tasks and to-dos, another for customers to schedule pickups and drop-offs, and a third for operations to keep all activities in the facilities in sync.
- > Participate in an on-call rotation to support production systems and investigate issues when they occur.
- > Write high-quality code that is well-tested, secure, and maintainable.
- Contribute directly to efforts through building features and frameworks, conducting code reviews, and participating in architecture and system design discussions.
- > Design and develop solutions able to process large volumes of data.
- ➤ Lead and participate in positioning our entire software stack both application and DevOps-related for success as we transition from a startup to a large organization.
- > Be instrumental in the transition from our monolith into Service Oriented Architecture.

Full Stack Developer Rextie.com Sept. 2018 – Feb. 2020 Lima, Peru · On Site **Rextie.com** is a currency exchange house.

Responsibilities

- > Provide mentorship and guidance to junior developers, helping them grow their skills and knowledge.
- > Write clean and reusable unit tests, integration, and end-to-end test development.
- > Lead by example in the practice and promotion of excellence in software engineering.
- > Help with root cause analysis, which may identify issues in the reporting, front end or even requirements.
- Collaborating with various cross-functional teams like design, product management, backend architects, and development teams to validate prototypes and to create elegant, usable, responsive, and interactive interfaces that meet client requirements.

<u>Full Stack Developer</u> MercadoChevere.com Dec. 2014 — Sept. 2018 Maturin, Venezuela · Remote

MercadoChevere.com was an e-commerce site, it is no longer active.

Responsibilities

- Implement Algolia as a search engine to perform quick and personalized searches of customers' publications.
- > Design and implement JAVA-based microservices for managing binary tree structured product categories, ensuring scalability and performance.
- Develop APIs for category management, allowing seamless integration with front-end interfaces and third-party services.
- Architect database schemas to efficiently store and query hierarchical product data, leveraging binary tree structures for optimized access.
- > Collaborate with front-end developers to ensure APIs meet the dynamic needs of the user interface, enhancing user experience.
- > Conduct thorough code reviews to maintain high code quality, focusing on readability, reusability, and maintainability.

EDUCATION

Professor of Informatics
University UPEL IPM | Aug. 2016
Maturin, Venezuela

INFORMATION

Languages: Fluent in English and Spanish.

As a dedicated Full Stack Developer with a passion for problem-solving and continuous learning, I am confident in my ability to contribute to your team's success. I look forward to discussing how my skills and experiences align with your needs. Thank you for considering my application.